Ryan Hatamosa

Full-Stack Software Engineer

301-323-5480 · ryan.hatamosa@gmail.com · Beltsville, MD · https://ryanhatamosa.vercel.app/ · /in/ryan-hatamosa/ · github.com/PinoyColada

I'm a recent graduate growth oriented and creative software engineer who specializes in building full-stack applications. Being an analytical problem solver, I am driven by the idea of constantly facing new challenges within the ever-changing field of technology. My love for programming elevates my projects from assumptions to facts and my code to real-world solutions. My collaborative nature and background in management enable me to become a valuable member of any team.

SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, Python, HTML, CSS | **Database** - PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firebase **Libraries and Frameworks** - React, Next.js, Flask , Express.js, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Pirate Plunders | React.js, Flask

- Led and actively contributed to the development of a pirate-themed space invaders game for my capstone class.
- Optimized project progress and efficiency by coordinating weekly planning meetings discussing project milestones, design progress, and test strategies.
- Designed and implemented a mobile-responsive, pixel art-inspired UI using pre-designed Figma mockups.
- Constructed a dynamic, real-time leaderboard with API integration, effectively recording players' scores and utilizing CSV file storage for data precision.

Body Sculptor | MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node.js

- Developed an application that tracks daily workouts by allowing users to record their work out routine.
- Incorporated RESTful API fetch calls to an Express, MongoDB, & Node.js backend handling all CRUD operations
- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections and deployed through Heroku.
- Tested all backend routes during development using Insomnia to ensure functionality.

Coder Typer | HTML, CSS, Javascript

- Created a typing game engaging users in rapid typing tests with a variety of code snippets.
- Incorporated an HTML/CSS-based page layout utilizing Flexbox for enhanced responsiveness and optimal user experience.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IT Technician, Astreya | Washington, DC

November 2023 - Present

- Offered on-site IT support to Google's conference rooms, managing inventory and conducting equipment maintenance
- Provided responsive face-to-face technical assistance to Google employees, swiftly resolving hardware and software issues and maintaining accurate records through ticketing systems.
- Collaborated with on-site teams at Google, deploying/recovering software images, troubleshooting computer issues, and contributing expertise to global IT projects for a seamless operational environment.

Software Engineer Intern, Amotions, Inc. | Burlingame, CA

August 2022 - October 2022

- Aided in the development of the website application designed for users to master soft skills through using React, TypeScript, and Firebase.
- Reformed stability of the application via everyday software maintenance across the codebase.
- Experienced executing practices that help promote collaboration and communication on team through daily stand-ups and pair programming.

Package Dispatch Supervisor, UPS | Laurel, MD

April 2018 - August 2022

- Ensured all assigned duties were completed on time by supervising package handlers and drivers daily.
- Improved service and company costs through overseeing load modifications.
- Maintained workplace safety and increased productivity by holding day to day pre-work communication meetings about employee performances and safety tips.

EDUCATION

University Of Maryland Global Campus - Remote

August 2022 – September 2023

Bachelor's in Computer Science, Dean's List 2023

Prince George's Community College | Largo, MD

August 2019- May 2021

Associates of Science in Computer Science, GPA: 3.0